A Guide to the Stanford Moore papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA111
Rockefeller Archive Center
Stanford Moore papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1881-1984, bulk 1913-1982
1913-1982
Rockefeller Archive Center
Moore, Stanford
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Stein, William H.
FA111
59.28 Cubic Feet 156 document cases
File Plan
Former Classification: I 450 M786
Biographical / Historical
Stanford Moore was born on September 4, 1913 in Chicago, Illinois, to John Howard and Ruth Fowler Moore. Moore grew up in Nashville, Tennessee, where his father was Professor of Law at Vanderbilt University. After attending Peabody Demonstration School, he enrolled at Vanderbilt, graduating with a B.S. in 1935. That same year, he began graduate studies in Chemistry at the University of Wisconsin. Under the supervision of Karl Paul Link, he produced his Ph.D. thesis, "The Identification of Carbohydrates as Benzimidazole Derivatives" in 1938. After obtaining his degree, Link recommended Moore for a research assistantship in the Max Bergmann Laboratory at the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research. Moore joined the Bergmann Laboratory in 1939, where he met his colleague and research partner of forty years, William H. Stein, a member of the laboratory since 1937.
During World War II, Moore served as a Technical Aide with the Office of Scientific Research and Development from 1942 to 1945. When the war ended, Herbert Gasser, then Director of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, offered Moore and Stein laboratory space at the Institute (Bergmann's laboratory no longer existed, as he had died in 1944). In 1945, Moore and Stein returned to the Institute to form the Moore-Stein Laboratory. For over forty years, until his death, Moore was a member of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (later the Rockefeller University). Moore primarily researched in the areas of chromatography and chemistry of carbohydrates, proteins, and amino acids, and had a keen interest in the development of scientific equipment.
In 1950, Moore accepted an invitation to the University of Brussels to be a visiting professor (Chaire Franqui/Francqui Chair), and followed up that appointment with a 6-month stint as an investigator at the University of Cambridge. He became a full Member of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research in 1952. Moore, together with Stein, worked to develop quantitative chromatographic methods through which proteins, peptides, and amino acids could be separated.
In 1972, Moore and Stein were awarded the Nobel Prize in Chemistry "for their contribution to the understanding of the connection between chemical structure and catalytic activity of the active centre of the ribonuclease molecule." They shared the award with Christian B. Anfinsen from the National Institutes of Health.
Moore was active in various professional scientific organizations, including the American Society of Biological Chemists (he served as President in 1967 as well as a member of the Editorial Board of the Journal of Biological Chemistry from 1950 to 1960), the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology (serving as president in 1971), and the International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry (he was secretary to the Commission on Proteins of the International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry from 1953 to 1957. In addition to the Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 1972, Moore (along with Stein) won the 1964 American Chemical Society Award in Chromatography and Electrophoresis, and the Richards Medal and the Linderstrøm-Lang Medal, both in 1972.
Stanford Moore died in his apartment in New York City on August 23, 1982 at the age of sixty-eight.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into eleven distinct series based on subject matter and media:
Series 1: Biographical and Family Material Series 2: Correspondence Series 3: Laboratory Files Series 4: Subject Files Series 5: Lectures and Speeches Series 6: Professional Travel and Activities Series 7: Nobel Prize Series 8: Manuscripts Series 9: Reprints Series 10: Audio-Visual Materials Series 11: Ephemera
Related Materials
For related material on Moore's work, the researcher may wish to consult:
FA127 William H. Stein papers, Rockefeller University Faculty (RU RG 450 St34)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: biographical material, correspondence, notes, speech materials, manuscripts, and various audio-visual materials.
Nobel Prize-winning scientists; Biology -- Research; Biochemistry; Chemistry; Chromatographic analysis
- Biographical and Family Material, 1881-1984; 1
  Arrangement
  Series 1, Biographical and Family Material, is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  Series 1, Biographical and Family Material, includes information on Moore's life as a whole, as well as Moore's childhood, adolescence, and early adulthood. Files on Moore's parents, Ruth Fowler and John Howard Moore, are also present in this series.
  - Bibliographies, 1940-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography of Chemical Literature, University of Wisconsin, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Material, 1960-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Biographical Memoirs by Emil L. Smith and C.H.W. Hirs, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Certificates, Diplomas, and Transcripts, 1931-1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1934-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Final Personal Note, August 20, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Moore Family Papers, 1881-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - John Howard Moore, "Vanderbilt Law Review", 1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ruth Fowler Moore Tribute, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ruth Frisbie Moore, Articles and Poems, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ruth Frisbie Moore, "The Bookman", 1930, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Notebook, "Animal Metabolism and Vitamins, Dr. Steenbock", 1936 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Notebook, "Differential Equations", 1934 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, "Experiments on Aromatic Compounds", 1934 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Notebook, "Laboratory Procedures, Biochemistry Research Laboratory, Dr. Karl Paul Link, University of Wisconsin", undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Notebook, "Physical Chemistry Experiments", 1935 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development Paperwork, 1942-1945 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "The Past is Prologue: Peabody Demonstration School 1915-1970" (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Ph.D. Thesis, "The Identification of Carbohydrates as Benzimidazole Derivatives", 1938 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - School Transcripts, 1930-1935 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Schoolboy Writings, 1929-1930; n.d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Textbook, "Laboratory Experiments in General Physics," by Philip Rudnick, Vanderbilt University (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Travel Documents, 1949-1981 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "The Peabody Volunteer", 1930 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "Volunteer," Peabody Demonstration School Yearbook, 1931, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, 1969-1981; 2
  Series 2, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by last name of the correspondent.
  Series 2, Correspondence, primarily contains professional and academic correspondence, and spans the years during which Moore was most active at the Institute/University.
  - A-Ag (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Ahrens, Edward H, Jr., 1969-1978 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Ai-All (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Alo-Au (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - B-Ban (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Bar-Bay (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Be-Bet (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Bh-Bou (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Birthday Correspondence - 65th Birthday (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Bow-Bur (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Busc-Bush (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Ca-Cas (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Cerami, Anthony, 1973-1981 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Ce-Co (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Christmas Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Cr-Cu (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - D-Dar (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Das-Daz (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Deb-Dey (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Di-Do (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Dr-Du (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - E-Ei (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - El-Ex (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - F-Fo (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Fr-Fu (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - G-Gh (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Gi-Go (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Gr-Gy (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Ha-Hay (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - He-Hi (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Ho-Hu (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - I (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - J (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Ka-Ki (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Kl-Kv (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - La-Le (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Lh-Liv (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Ll-Ly (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Maa-Mat (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Mau-Mi (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Mo-My (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - N (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - O (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Pa-Pe (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Ph-Pon (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Pop-Pu (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - R-Ray (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Re-Rey (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - Ri-Ry (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - S-Sa (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - Sc-Scr (Box 11, Folder 77)
  - Se (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - Seitz, Frederick (Box 11, Folder 81, Folder 79, Folder 80)
  - Sel-Sh (Box 11, Folder 82)
  - Si-Sm (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - Sn-So (Box 12, Folder 84)
  - Sp-St (Box 12, Folder 85)
  - Su-Sz (Box 12, Folder 86)
  - R-Te (Box 12, Folder 87)
  - Th-Tu (Box 12, Folder 88)
  - U (Box 12, Folder 89)
  - V (Box 13, Folder 90)
  - W-We (Box 13, Folder 91)
  - Wh-Wi (Box 13, Folder 92)
  - Wl-Wy (Box 13, Folder 93)
  - X (Box 13, Folder 94)
  - Y (Box 13, Folder 95)
  - Z (Box 13, Folder 96)
  - Unidentified or Illegible (Box 14, Folder 97)
- Laboratory Files, 1954-1976; 3
  Series 3, Laboratory Files, is further separated into two categories: Laboratory Administration and Laboratory Notes and Notebooks. The series is arranged alphabetcially.
  Series 3, Laboratory Files, contains files on members and associates of the Moore-Stein Laboratory at the Institute/University, as well as notes and notebooks by Moore and others.
  - Laboratory Administration
    - Seetharama A. Acharya (Box 14, Folder 98, Folder 98A)
    - Lorraine Ackerman (Box 14, Folder 98B)
    - Active Mailing List (Box 14, Folder 99)
    - Analyzer Project (Box 14, Folder 100)
    - J. Leggett Bailey (Box 14, Folder 101)
    - Jacques Bartholeyns (Box 14, Folder 102, Folder 103, Box 15, Folder 104)
    - S. Theodore Bella (Box 15, Folder 105)
    - Peter Blackburn (Box 15, Folder 106A, Folder 106, Folder 108, Folder 107)
    - M. Prince Brigham (Box 15, Folder 109)
    - L. Eugene Burton (Box 15, Folder 110, Box 16, Folder 111)
    - Michael Bustin (Box 17, Folder 116, Box 16, Folder 112, Folder 113, Folder 114, Folder 115)
    - Anne Capuano (Box 17, Folder 117, Folder 117A)
    - Brian J. Catley (Box 17, Folder 118)
    - Roger D. Cole (Box 17, Folder 120, Folder 119)
    - Charles F. Crampton (Box 17, Folder 121)
    - Arthur M. Crestfield (Box 18, Folder 122, Folder 122A)
    - Arthur M. Crestfield, Sample Injectors (Box 18, Folder 123)
    - D-500 Analyses (Box 18, Folder 124)
    - Grace Dean (Box 18, Folder 125)
    - Harold F. Deutsch (Box 18, Folder 126)
    - Alberto Di Donato (Box 18, Folder 127)
    - T.A.A. Dopheide (Box 18, Folder 128)
    - Robert J. Drummond (Box 18, Folder 129, Box 19, Folder 130)
    - Allen B. Edmundson (Box 19, Folder 131)
    - Michael Eidelberg (Box 19, Folder 132)
    - Wendy J. Fantl (Box 19, Folder 133)
    - William Ferdinand (Box 19, Folder 134)
    - Paul L. Fletcher, Jr. (Box 19, Folder 136, Folder 135A, Folder 135)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Folder 135A contains restricted material.
    - Noreen Fucci (Box 20, Folder 137A, Folder 137)
      Folder 137A is restricted.
    - José G. Gavilanes (Box 20, Folder 138A, Folder 138)
      Folder 138A is restricted.
    - Brenda I. Gerwin (Box 20, Folder 139)
    - Dana Giulian (Box 20, Folder 141, Folder 140)
    - A.R. Goldberg (Box 20, Folder 142)
    - Goodman (Box 20, Folder 143)
    - Arabinda Guha (Box 21, Folder 145, Folder 144, Folder 144A)
      Folder 144A is restricted
    - Gerd Gundlach (Box 21, Folder 146, Folder 146A)
      Folder 146A is restricted.
    - Rikimaru Hayashi (Box 21, Folder 148, Folder 147, Folder 147A)
      Folder 147A is restricted
    - Robert L. Heinrikson (Box 22, Folder 149)
    - C.H.W. Hirs (Box 22, Folder 150)
    - Jan Hofsteenge (Box 22, Folder 151, Folder 152A, Folder 152)
      Folder 152A is restricted
    - Allen Holt (Box 22, Folder 153A, Folder 153)
      Folder 153A is resticted
    - Tony E. Hugli (Box 23, Folder 154, Folder 154A, Folder 156, Folder 155)
      Folder 154A is restricted
    - Inventory (Box 23, Folder 157)
    - Inventory of Gas Tanks (Box 23, Folder 158)
    - Eric Jaffe (Box 23, Folder 159)
    - Bansi Lal Jailkhani (Box 23, Folder 160, Folder 160A)
      Folder 160A is restricted
    - Glyn Jones (Box 23, Folder 161)
    - Julia Kaminskaya (Box 24, Folder 162, Folder 162A)
      Folder 162A is restricted
    - Kitano (Box 24, Folder 163)
    - Choong Kil Lee (Box 24, Folder 164)
    - Ta-Hsiu Liao (Box 24, Folder 165, Folder 165A, Folder 166, Folder 167)
      Folder 165A is restricted
    - Michael Ching-Chung Lin (Box 24, Folder 168A, Box 25, Folder 169, Folder 168)
      Folder 168A is restricted
    - Teh-Yung Liu (Box 25, Folder 170, Folder 171, Folder 172)
    - Roger L. Lundblad (Box 26, Folder 173, Folder 174, Folder 173A)
      Folder 173A is restricted
    - Richard McCaman (Box 26, Folder 175)
    - Members of the Bergmann and Moore-Stein Laboratories (Box 26, Folder 176)
    - Victor R. Michalak (Box 26, Folder 177)
    - Milton Roy Company (Box 26, Folder 178)
    - Paul Hershell B. Montalban (Box 26, Folder 179, Folder 179A)
      Folder 179A is resticted
    - Phyllis Moses (Box 26, Folder 180)
    - Norbert Neumann (Box 26, Folder 181A, Folder 181)
      Folder 181A is restricted
    - Alan M. Nigen (Box 26, Folder 182A, Folder 182)
      Folder 182A is restricted
    - Njifutie Njikam (Box 26, Folder 183A, Folder 183)
      Folder 183A is restricted
    - NS 09639 (Box 27, Folder 184, Folder 184A)
      Folder 184A is restricted
    - NS 09639 - First 5 Years (Box 27, Folder 186, Folder 185, Folder 185A)
      Folder 185A is restricted
    - NSF Grant, USA-Italy (Box 27, Folder 188A, Folder 187, Folder 188)
      Folder 188A is restricted
    - Optical Equipment (Box 27, Folder 189)
    - Shoshi Ota (Box 28, Folder 190A, Folder 190)
      Folder 190A is restricted
    - Alejandro C. Paladini (Box 28, Folder 191)
    - Frances S. Pearson (Box 28, Folder 192)
    - Personnel (Box 28, Folder 193)
      Restricted material - personnel records
    - Bryce V. Plapp (Box 28, Folder 194A, Folder 195, Folder 194)
      Folder 194A is restricted
    - Maria A. Pospischil (Box 28, Folder 196A, Folder 196)
      Folder 196A is restricted
    - Paul Price (Box 29, Folder 198, Box 28, Folder 197)
    - T.G. Rajagopalan (Box 29, Folder 199A, Folder 199)
      Folder 199A is restricted
    - Seetharam Ramnath (Box 29, Folder 200, Folder 200A)
      Folder 200A is restricted
    - Recorder (Box 29, Folder 201)
    - Research Associate Search (Box 29, Folder 202A, Folder 202)
      Folder 202A is restricted
    - Research Schedule (Box 29, Folder 203)
    - Martin Rizack (Box 29, Folder 204)
    - George W. Robinson (Box 29, Folder 205A, Folder 205)
      Folder 205A is restricted
    - Daniel Rudman (Box 29, Folder 206)
    - John C. Saari (Box 30, Folder 207, Folder 207A)
      Folder 207A is restricted
    - Johann Salnikow (Box 30, Folder 208)
    - Ira J. Salzman (Box 30, Folder 209)
    - Schedules, Account Numbers, Diagrams (Box 30, Folder 210)
    - Hans-Georg Schleich (Box 30, Folder 211)
    - Ernesto Scoffone (Box 31, Folder 213, Box 30, Folder 212A, Folder 212)
      Folder 212A is restricted
    - Lo Shan-Shan (Box 31, Folder 214)
    - Denis Shaw (Box 31, Folder 215)
    - Janusz Skupin (Box 31, Folder 216A, Folder 216)
      Folder 216A is restricted
    - Derek Smyth (Box 31, Folder 218, Folder 217)
    - David C. Sogin (Box 31, Folder 219, Folder 219A, Box 32, Folder 220, Folder 221)
      Folder 219A is restricted
    - Steve Sommer (Box 32, Folder 222)
    - Thomas S. Soper (Box 32, Folder 223, Folder 223A)
      Folder 223A is restricted
    - Darrel H. Spackman (Box 33, Folder 226, Box 32, Folder 224, Folder 225)
    - George R. Stark (Box 33, Folder 227, Folder 228, Folder 229, Folder 230, Folder 230A)
      Folder 230A is restricted
    - George R. Stark, Tryptophan Analysis (Box 33, Folder 231)
    - William H. Stein (Box 34, Folder 235, Folder 234, Folder 233, Folder 232)
    - Richard Sterner (Box 34, Folder 236)
    - Kenji Takahashi (Box 35, Folder 239, Folder 238, Box 34, Folder 237A, Folder 237)
      Folder 237A is restricted
    - Harris H. Tallan (Box 35, Folder 241, Folder 240)
    - G.P. Talwar (Box 35, Folder 242)
    - Technicians (Box 35, Folder 243)
      Folder 243 is restricted
    - Telephone Extension Information (Box 35, Folder 244)
    - Moshe Trop (Box 35, Folder 245A, Folder 245)
      Folder 245A is restricted
    - Hiroshi Ueno (Box 36, Folder 246)
    - Unlabeled and Loose Laboratory Administration Materials (Box 36, Folder 247A, Folder 247)
      Folder 247A is restricted
    - Mayo Uziel (Box 36, Folder 248)
    - Vacation Schedules (Box 36, Folder 249)
      Restricted material
    - Dalton Wang (Box 36, Folder 253, Folder 251, Folder 252, Folder 250, Folder 250A)
      Folder 250A is restricted
    - Jing-yan Wang (Box 36, Folder 254)
    - Aster Deborah White (Box 37, Folder 255, Folder 255A)
      Folder 255A is restricted
    - Glynn Wilson (Box 37, Folder 256A, Folder 256, Folder 259, Folder 257, Folder 258)
      Folder 256A is restricted
  - Laboratory Notes and Notebooks, 1954-1976
    - Arabinda (Box 38, Folder 260)
    - Chemistry of Ninhydrin (Box 38, Folder 261)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S1-S7, 1954 (Box 38, Folder 262)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S8-S37, 1954 (Box 38, Folder 263)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S38-S67, 1954-1955 (Box 38, Folder 264)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S68-S95, 1955 (Box 38, Folder 265)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S96-S115, 1955 (Box 38, Folder 266)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S116-S133, 1955 (Box 38, Folder 267)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S164-S155, 1955 (Box 39, Folder 268)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S156-S174, 1955 (Box 39, Folder 269)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S175-S195, 1955-1956 (Box 39, Folder 270)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S197-S223, 1956 (Box 39, Folder 271)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S224-S256, 1956 (Box 39, Folder 272)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S263-S291, 1956 (Box 39, Folder 273)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S292-S335, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 274)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers S336-S360, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 275)
    - Chromatogram Notebook, Numbers 679-728, 1958 (Box 40, Folder 276)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers 790-849, 1958-1959 (Box 40, Folder 277)
    - Chromatogram Notebook, Numbers 791-819, 1958 (Box 40, Folder 278)
    - Chromatogram Notebook, Numbers 848-885, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 279)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers 852-825, 1-953 - 1-1025, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 280)
    - Chromatogram Notebook, Numbers 900-925, 1959 (Box 41, Folder 281)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers 1-1036 - 1-1170, 1959 (Box 41, Folder 282)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers 1-1105 - 1-1189, 1959-1960 (Box 41, Folder 283)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers 1-1191 - 1-1554, 1960-1961 (Box 41, Folder 284)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers 1-1560 - 1-2053, 1961-1963 (Box 42, Folder 285)
    - Chromatograms, Numbers 1-2103 - 1-2402, 1963-1964 (Box 42, Folder 286)
    - Chromatograph Data (Box 42, Folder 287)
    - Chymotrypsin (Box 42, Folder 288)
    - Constants (Box 42, Folder 289)
    - D-500, Aspartame, 1974 (Box 42, Folder 290)
    - Data Sheets - S900 (Box 42, Folder 291)
    - Distribution Coefficients (Box 42, Folder 292)
    - Disulfide Interchange Notebook 1, Chromatograms, Numbers 768-758, 1958 (Box 42, Folder 293)
    - Disulfide Interchange Notebook 1, Chromatograms, Numbers 762-809, 1958 (Box 43, Folder 294)
    - Disulfide Studies, Chromatogram Notebook, Numbers S250-S319, 1956 (Box 43, Folder 295)
    - Disulfide Studies, Chromatogram Notebook, Numbers 848-895, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 296)
    - DPN (Box 43, Folder 297)
    - Durrum Analyzer, 1971-1972 (Box 43, Folder 298)
    - Durrum D-500 (Box 43, Folder 299)
    - Eye - Chemistry (Box 43, Folder 300)
    - Feder (Box 43, Folder 301)
    - Fulpius Chromatograms (Box 43, Folder 302)
    - Giulian (Box 43, Folder 303)
    - Hemoperfusion (Box 43, Folder 304)
    - Hemoperfusion (Box 43, Folder 305)
    - Instrumentation (Box 43, Folder 306)
    - Isopiestic Method (Box 43, Folder 307)
    - Julian (Box 43, Folder 308)
    - Araxie Kilejian (Box 43, Folder 309)
    - Larsen (Box 43, Folder 310)
    - Choong Kil Lee, Toxin, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 311)
    - C.K. Lee, Toxins (Box 43, Folder 311A)
    - Lingappa (Box 44, Folder 312)
    - Karl Paul Link, Carbohydrates (Box 44, Folder 313)
    - Peter Model (Box 44, Folder 314)
    - Moore, Thermodynamics, Daniels (Box 44, Folder 315)
    - Moore, Thermodynamics, Daniels (Box 44, Folder 316)
    - Mounted Protein Chart (Box 44, Folder 317)
    - Ninhydrin, Volume 1 (Box 44, Folder 318)
    - Ninhydrin, Volume 2 (Box 44, Folder 319)
    - Ninhydrin, Volume 3 (Box 44, Folder 320)
    - Ninhydrin, Volume 4 (Box 45, Folder 321)
    - Ninhydrin, Volume 5 (Box 45, Folder 322)
    - Operating Instructions and Schematics for Fraction Collector Control System (Box 45, Folder 323)
    - Operation and Maintenance Manual, Model D-500 Amino Acid Analyzer (Box 45, Folder 324)
    - Pomerantz (Box 45, Folder 325)
    - Preparation of Starch, etc., Drop Sizes (Box 45, Folder 327)
    - Prystowsky (Box 45, Folder 328)
    - Protein Hydrolysis (Box 45, Folder 330)
    - Recorded Curves, 1958 (Box 45, Folder 331)
    - Recorder (Box 45, Folder 332)
    - Recorder (Box 45, Folder 333)
    - Research Notes (Box 46, Folder 333)
    - RNase on Cells, (Notebook) 1 (Box 46, Folder 334)
    - RNase on Cells, (Notebook) 2 (Box 46, Folder 335)
    - Scheele (Box 46, Folder 336)
    - Andreas Scheid (Box 46, Folder 337)
    - Siekevitz, Tzeng, and Cohen (Box 46, Folder 338)
    - Darrel H. Spackman, Book SA (Box 46, Folder 339)
    - Darrel H. Spackman, Notebook, 1955-1957 (Box 46, Folder 340)
    - Darrel H. Spackman, Notebook, 1957-1959 (Box 46, Folder 341)
    - Standard Solutions (Box 46, Folder 342)
    - Kenneth Sterling (Box 46, Folder 343)
    - Synthetic Mixture (Box 46, Folder 344)
    - Tryptophan, Binder (Box 46, Folder 345)
    - Tryptophan Project (Box 46, Folder 346)
    - Unidentified (Box 47, Folder 347)
    - Unlabeled Binder, 1975-1976 (Box 47, Folder 348)
    - Unlabeled Notebook (Box 47, Folder 349)
    - Unlabeled Notebook, 1972-1973 (Box 47, Folder 350)
    - Unlabeled Notes (Box 47, Folder 351)
    - Unlabeled Notes 1 (Box 47, Folder 352)
    - Unlabeled Notes 2 (Box 47, Folder 353)
    - Unlabeled Notes 3 (Box 47, Folder 354)
    - Unlabeled Notes 4 (Box 47, Folder 355)
    - Unlabeled Notes 5 (Box 47, Folder 356)
    - Unlabeled Notes 6 (Box 47, Folder 357)
    - Wilson/Blackburn, Cell Surface/RNase Dimer (Box 47, Folder 358)
- Subject Files, 1974-1976; 4
  Series 4, Subject Files, is arranged alphabetically.
  Series 4, Subject Files contains material collected by Moore on various topics, including people, places, events, and research subjects. These files can include articles, notes, reprints, and correspondence.
  - 150th Anniversary of Wöhler's Synthesis of Urea (Box 48, Folder 359)